I'm having the same issue. would love to see it fixed
---
Independent confirmation of this on `7.0.0-rc14`, with the root cause traced end to end. The
cause was already identified in #2627 and acknowledged there, but that issue was closed by the
stale bot on 21 Jul with `state_reason: completed` — nothing was actually changed, and `master`
still carries the code today.

### Root cause

`Socket/socket.ts` announces the push name on every `creds.update`:

```ts
ev.on('creds.update', update => {
  const name = update.me?.name
  // if name has just been received
  if (creds.me?.name !== name) {
    logger.debug({ name }, 'updated pushName')
    sendNode({ tag: 'presence', attrs: { name: name! } })
    ...
```

Three things combine, and the third is what makes it continuous rather than a one-off:

1. **The comparison misfires on partial updates.** When an update carries no `me`, `name` is
   `undefined`, so `creds.me?.name !== undefined` is `true` for any session that has a stored
   push name. The `name!` assertion is exactly the assumption that does not hold here.
2. **The node is typeless, which means _available_.** `WABinary/encode.ts` filters out
   `undefined` attributes, so `attrs: { name: undefined }` serialises to a bare `<presence/>`.
   Baileys' own inbound reader in `Socket/chats.ts` treats that as online:
   `attrs.type === 'unavailable' ? 'unavailable' : 'available'`. Nothing is logged, because the
   send succeeds.
3. **`creds.update` fires per incoming message.** It is emitted from `Socket/messages-recv.ts`
   (among many other places), so ordinary key churn triggers the announcement continuously —
   not only right after pairing, which is why `markOnlineOnConnect: false` looks like it is
   being ignored.

### Reproduction (no send required)

Read-only client, `markOnlineOnConnect: false`, already paired:

1. Leave the primary phone **locked and untouched**, and confirm from a third account that the
   number reads as offline.
2. Send a message to it from a second account.
3. The number goes **online** for several minutes, without the phone ever being opened.

Repeating step 2 keeps it online. That also reproduces the push-notification suppression in the
opening report: the account is online, so WhatsApp stops pushing to the phone.

### Fix

The one proposed in #2627 is correct and still applies to `master`:

```ts
if (typeof name === 'string' && name.length > 0 && creds.me?.name !== name) {
```

Real push-name updates still get announced; partial credential patches no longer do.

### Workaround, for anyone blocked before that lands

Without patching the package, normalise the payload before the library's own listener sees it,
using the public event surface — attach the stored `me` to updates that carry none, so the
comparison finds no change:

```ts
const passThrough = sock.ev.emit.bind(sock.ev)
sock.ev.emit = (event, data) => {
  if (event === 'creds.update' && data && (data as any).me === undefined && state.creds.me) {
    return passThrough(event, { ...(data as object), me: state.creds.me })
  }
  return passThrough(event, data)
}
```

For a read-only client this is the difference between an account that is silently online all day
and one that is not, so it would be good to see the one-line guard land. Happy to open a PR if
that is useful.

---
Same root cause here, on a personal (non-bot) number - opened #2789 with the one-line guard from #2627 plus the regression test that PR was missing.

Worth adding one thing to the report, because it changes who this affects: on a number that a human actually uses, this presents as WhatsApp silently never notifying you again. Messages only show up when you open the app. Calls keep working, because they come in over a separate VoIP path that ignores presence - so it reads as a broken phone, not a broken linked client. I went through every iOS notification setting and was about to reinstall the app before I suspected my own bridge.

Verified on `7.0.0-rc14` and on current `master`: `socket.ts:1054` misfires on any partial update, `encode.ts:226` strips the undefined attr so the node goes out bare, and `chats.ts:885` reads a typeless presence node as `available`.

